Guide to the Roger W. Moss Collection of Manuscript, Original Art and Printed Material by and about Richard Shirley Smith
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Ephemera, Series V
  - Letterheads: Murray Williams & Company, between 1980 and 2000?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 4 sheets; 16 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Four identical memo-sized sheets of paper bearing the letterhead of Murray Williams & Company (Penzance). The letterhead design (unillustrated) is presumably by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Letterheads; Murray Williams & Company
  - Letterheads: Leonis Limited. J.A. McAlpine, R. Antis., circa 2000?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 sheets; 30 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Two identical sheets of A4 paper bearing the letterhead of Leonis Limited, J.A. McAlpine, R. Antis (London). The letterhead design, presumably by Richard Shirley Smith, features a lion-head door knocker.
  - Letterhead: Henbury Hall, Macclesfield, Cheshire, 2000s?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 30 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Blank sheet of A4 paper bearing the letterhead of Henbury Hall. The letterhead design features an image of the Hall.
    Letterheads; Henbury Hall (Henbury, England)
  - Examples of bookplates made as wood engravings by Simon Brett., circa 2000?; Brett, Simon, 1943-; 7 sheets (Box 1, Folder 70)
    Six wood-engraved bookplates by Simon Brett, with a sheet explaining the wood engraving process. Includes bookplates for: Julian Berkely, The Folio Society, John Gartner, Barry T. Jackson, Richard Maurice Cameron Leach, and Liesel & Walter Schwab.
    Wood engravings; Bookplates; Brett, Simon, 1943-
  - Proofs from the Folio Society edition of Virgil's Eclogues, with decorations by Shirley Smith, 2000; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 folded sheet; 25 x 34 cm, folded to 25 x 17 cm (Box 3, Folder add. 5)
  - Photocopy of an obituary for Percy Young, from The Independent, 2004 May 15; 1; sheets (Box 3, Folder add. 6)
    Obituaries; Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004
- Correspondence, Series VI
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2000 July 3; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Moss commissions Shirley Smith to design a bookplate for the Athenaeum of Philadelphia, Roger W. Moss Fund.
    Correspondence; Bookplates; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Athenaeum of Philadelphia; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2000 July 4; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 24 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Shirley Smith expresses interest in designing the bookplate for Moss and describes his terms. He encloses an outline of the terms.
    Correspondence; Bookplates; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2000 January 11; Shirley Smith, Richard; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Shirley Smith and Moss discuss the bookplate design. Rough sketches enclosed.
  - Correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2000 September 6; Shirley Smith, Richard; 5 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Moss makes suggestions on Shirley Smith's design. Shirley Smith encloses four photocopies of the proof.
    Correspondence; Bookplates; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2000 September 25; Brett, Simon, 1943-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Brett replies to Moss's bookplate design inquiry with information about the cost and design process.
    Correspondence; Bookplates; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Brett, Simon, 1943-
  - Correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2000 September 25; Shirley Smith, Richard; 5 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Shirley Smith encloses a transparency of his painting Empty tombs and photocopies of the bookplate proof. Moss thanks him and requests two changes to the bookplate design.
  - Fax to Richard Shirley Smith c/o Brian Bailey, 2000 September 26; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 4 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Shirley Smith discusses revisions to his bookplate design. Moss approves Shirley Smith's latest design and asks for an estimate for 500 of each version of the bookplate.
  - Fax to Roger W. Moss, 2000 September 27; Shirley Smith, Richard; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Shirley Smith thanks Moss for the "Rome" book and provides a printing estimate for the bookplates.
  - Fax to Brian Bailey, 2000 November 13; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Moss asks Brian Bailey (of Libanus Press) to let Shirley Smith know the package arrived and requests the invoice.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Bailey, Brian; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Libanus Press
  - Fax to Richard Shirley Smith c/o Brian Bailey, 2001 February 14; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Moss inquires about visiting Shirley Smith in June.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Fax to Richard Shirley Smith c/o Brian Bailey, 2000 September 28; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Moss sends the second half of the bookplate fee and lists the items in his Richard Shirley Smith collection.
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2000 October 4; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 24 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Shirley Smith thanks Moss for his last payment and discusses transportation costs for the bookplates, paintings and original art work.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2000 October 18; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 15 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Shirley Smith describes details for shipping a parcel of art work.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2000 November 13; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Moss encloses a list of his current collection of Shirley Smith's work and expresses interest in sponsoring an exhibition at the Athenaeum of Philadelphia.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Athenaeum of Philadelphia
  - Letter to Audrey Spencer Arellanes, 2000 November 16; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 6 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Moss sends Arellanes an essay he has written about Shirley Smith's work. Essay is enclosed.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Arellanes, Audrey Spencer
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2000 November 18; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 24 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Shirley Smith discusses details of a potential exhibition at the Athenaeum of Philadelphia.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard -- Exhibitions; Athenaeum of Philadelphia
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2000 November 27; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Moss discusses setting up two U.S. exhibitions for Shirley Smith.
  - Invoice from Libanus Press, 2000 December 5; Libanus Press; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Invoice; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Libanus Press -- Correspondence
  - New Year's greeting card to Roger and Gail Moss, 2001 January; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 greeting card; 15.7 x 20.7 cm (Box 2, Folder 18b)
    Greeting cards; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2001 February 21; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 24 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Shirley Smith discusses Moss's upcoming visit.
    Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Photocopy of final bookplate proof, 2001 February; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Inscribed in graphite: "This version approved to print. 500 copies. R.W. Moss."
    Photocopies; Bookplates; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2001 February 28; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Moss discusses the Santa Fe art market and the arrangements for his upcoming visit to Marlborough. Moss encloses a letter in which he introduces Shirley Smith to Klaudia Maria Marr of the Griff Gallery in Santa Fe.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Marr, Klaudia Maria
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2001 March 25; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 24 x 16 cm (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Shirley Smith discusses Moss's upcoming visit to Marlborough and thanks him for the information regarding Santa Fe.
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2001 May 23; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Shirley Smith provides Moss with information regarding train schedules for his upcoming visit.
    Electronic mail; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2001 June 12; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Moss and Shirley Smith discuss the possibility of commissioning John McGill in Cambridge to cast a foot for Moss.
    Electronic mail; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; McGill, John, 1934-
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2001 June 19; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 24a)
    Moss reflects on his recent visit to Shirley Smith's home and studio in Marlborough and thanks him for hosting.
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2001 June 27; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 22 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 24b)
    Shirley Smith discusses his three "Asia Minor" paintings and transporting work to Klaudia Marr in Santa Fe.
  - Letter to Gail Wingler and Roger W. Moss, 2001 July 24; Jones, Peter, 1956-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Jones discusses George W. Bush and Thorstein Veblen's The theory of the leisure class.
    Correspondence; Jones, Peter, 1956-; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Wingler, Gail; Veblen, Thorstein, 1857-1929; Bush, George W. (George Walker), 1946-
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2001 July 24; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Shirley Smith gives the measurements for his painting Giant Egg and Dart.
    Electronic mail; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2001 October 22; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Shirley Smith discusses his painting Giant Egg and Dart and Sir John Soane's Museum.
    Electronic mail; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Sir John Soane's Museum
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2001 November 25; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Shirley Smith discusses transportation for Giant Egg and Dart.
  - Photographs of Richard Shirley Smith's work, 2001?; 5 photographs; 18 x 12.5 cm and smaller (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Brochure for the Ivy House Hotel and Scotts Restaurant, 2001?; 8 pages; 21 x 15 cm (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Letter to Clive Aslet, 2002 February 7; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Moss discusses the exhibition and launch of Richard Shirley Smith: The Paintings & Collages, 1957-2000, and suggests it may appeal to the Country Life magazine audience.
    Correspondence; Aslet, Clive, 1955-; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard -- Exhibitions
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2002 February 6; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Shirley Smith confirms that the money arrived for Giant Egg and Dart.
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2002 February 4; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Moss discusses his book launch and solo show at the Chris Beetles Gallery.
    Electronic mail; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Chris Beetles Limited
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2002 March 4; Aslet, Clive, 1955-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Aslet thanks Moss for informing him about the Richard Shirley Smith book and exhibition.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Aslet, Clive, 1955-
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2002 March 15; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 34a)
    Shirley Smith discusses his upcoming book launch and exhibition.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard -- Exhibitions
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2002 March 22; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Shirley Smith discusses the book launch at the Chris Beetles Gallery.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Chris Beetles Limited
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2002 January 28; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Moss congratulates Shirley Smith on the book launch and says that he will attend the launch and exhibition at the Chris Beetles Gallery in April.
  - Price list for works featured in The Paintings and Collages 1957-2000, 2002?; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2002 May 23; Shirley Smith, Richard; 4 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Shirley Smith discusses Moss's recent visit to Marlborough.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2002 September 4; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Moss invites Shirley Smith and Rosemarie to dinner at the Park Street flat in October.
  - Letter to Roger and Gail Moss, 2002; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 22.5 x 15.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Shirley Smith wishes Moss a happy New Year and mentions several projects he is working on.
  - Email to Gail and Roger Moss, 2002 October 7; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Shirley Smith discusses the Harrow School private view.
    Electronic mail; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Harrow School. Old Speech Room Gallery
  - Order form for Building Towers, forming Gardens (Landscaping by Hamilton, Hoare and Beckford) by Dr. Christopher Thacker, 2002?; St. Barnabas Press; 4 pages; 21 x 15 cm (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Inscribed in ink next to ISBN numbers: "Not good. The limited edition has just come out with 4 color illustrations and 4 signed engravings."
  - Letter to Roger and Gail Moss, 2003 February 3; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Shirley Smith discusses the Harrow School exhibition and encloses a flyer for the show. The letter is written on the back of a Harrow School parking map.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Harrow School. Old Speech Room Gallery; Shirley Smith, Richard -- Exhibitions
  - Correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2003 September 3; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Shirley Smith discusses the limited edition of Building Towers, Forming Gardens and a large mural he is working on. Moss discusses his completion of Historic Sacred Places of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2004 January 5; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 7 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Moss discusses his new cottage in Maine, his retirement, and recent projects. Attached are copies of preliminary pages of The Finzi Book Room at the University of Reading: A Catalogue by Pauline Dingley.
  - Letter to Roger and Gail Moss, 2004 May 25; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Shirley Smith discusses his recent mural work.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2004 May 30; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Moss discusses his retirement, the publication of Historic Sacred Places of Philadelphia, and further collection of Shirley Smith's work.
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, circa 2005?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 15 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Shirley Smith discusses relocation for the Finzi English Literature Library, which the Reading University has decided to close.
  - Letter Roger Moss, circa 2005?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page, 2 photographs; 15 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Smith discusses payment and shipment for three books that Moss purchased. He encloses two photographs of a mural.
    Correspondence; Photographs; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Email to Roger Moss, 2006 January 28; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Shirley Smith discusses payment for a parcel of books.
  - Email correspondence between Simon Lawrence and Roger W. Moss, 2006 February 6; Lawrence, Simon, 1958-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Two copies. Moss requests one of the 40 limited edition copies of Shirley Smith's bookplate and Lawrence replies with payment details.
    Electronic mail; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Lawrence, Simon, 1958-
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2006 February 8; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Moss discusses sending a payment to Shirley Smith, his cottage house in Maine, and a bookplate exhibition at the Athenaeum of Philadelphia.
    Electronic mail; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Athenaeum of Philadelphia
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2006 March 29; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 52a)
    Moss discusses the inclusion of Shirley Smith's work in an exhibition of international bookplates at the Athenaeum of Philadelphia.
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2006 April 9; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Moss discusses the exhibition at the Athenaeum of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2006?; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Moss discusses his retirement and a potential visit to Windsor Castle with the American Friends of the Attingham Trust in the next year.
  - Correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2007 January 23; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 4 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 55)
    Moss discusses his house in Maine and the bookplate exhibition assembled by the American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers at the Athenaeum. Shirley Smith thanks Moss for showing his bookplates in the exhibition and discusses Simon Lawrence's Barnett Freedman.
    Correspondence; Bookplates; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Lawrence, Simon, 1958-; American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers
  - New Year's greeting card to Roger W. Moss, 2008 January; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 greeting card; 16 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 56)
    Shirley Smith discusses the Bodleian Library's request for his archive and his painting Pulcinella Engine Driver (cover of greeting card).
    Greeting cards; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Bodleian Library
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2008 May 8; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Moss discusses his upcoming visit to study Royal Collections at Windsor Palace.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Windsor Castle
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2008 September 15; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 58)
    Moss reflects on the two days he spent with Shirley Smith including their lunch with Roy Strong and visit to see the Laskett Gardens.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Strong, Roy; Laskett Gardens
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2008 September 29; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 24 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Shirley Smith discusses giving 21 of his best engravings to the Department of Prints and Drawings at the British Museum. He includes three comic drawings on the second page.
    Correspondence; Pen and ink drawings; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; British Museum
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2008 November 22; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 60)
    Moss discusses his publication of Historic Landmarks of Philadelphia and the British Museum's acquisition of Shirley Smith's engravings.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; British Museum
  - List of Richard Shirley Smith's book illustrations and items missing from the collection, 2009 April 6; Shirley Smith, Richard; 3 pages; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Email correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2009 April 20; Shirley Smith, Richard; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 62)
    Moss asks Shirley Smith to sign the bookplates for the exhibition and attaches a chronological inventory of work for his review.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 April 12; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 63)
    Moss discusses his inventory of Shirley Smith's bookplates and books and finding a repository for the collection in the United States.
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2009 April?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 24.5 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 64)
    Shirley Smith discusses Moss's inventory of his work and encloses a list of four additional items Moss may not have.
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 April 27; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 65)
    Moss thanks Shirley Smith for the additions to his bookplate collection.
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2009 April 28; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 66)
    Shirley Smith thanks Moss for his letter.
  - Email correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2009 May 4; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 3 pages; 29.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 67)
    Moss discusses a house museum he helped restore in Deadwood, South Dakota, and suggests inquiring into printing the Moss Collection bibliography through Libanus Press. Attached is a list of works Shirley Smith offers to add to the collection. Moss also encloses a photograph of "Cycle of Life" and six photographs of an unidentified location depicting frescos, which appear to be the work of Shirley Smith.
  - Email correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2009 May 22; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 68)
    Shirley Smith and Moss discuss shipping arrangements for an LP record cover and vocal score covers.
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2009 June 5; Shirley Smith, Richard; 4 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 69)
    Shirley Smith discusses shipping a parcel of vocal score covers to Moss.
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2009 June 4; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 29.5 x 21 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    Shirley Smith discusses the John E. Rovensky art collection. He encloses a 1957 clipping from the New Yorker regarding a Rovensky auction at the Parke-Bernet Galleries.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Rovensky, John E. (John Edward), 1880-1970
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 June 11; Shirley Smith, Richard; 5 pages; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 71)
    Moss discusses English usage of hyphenated surnames and John E. Rovensky art collection sales notices.
    Electronic mail; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Rovensky, John E. (John Edward), 1880-1970
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 June 24; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 29 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 72)
    Moss reports on the arrival of a package from Shirley Smith.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 June 25; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 73)
    Moss discusses arrival of the package from Shirley Smith, which includes book cover designs Despatches, Water & Life and Tale of Two Cities among others.
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 July 2; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 74)
    Moss reports that Shirley Smith's package has arrived safely and discusses payment.
  - Email to Simon Lawrence, 2009 July 2; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 75)
    Moss discusses transferring funds to Shirley Smith and asks if Fleece Press would be interested in printing a checklist/bibliography of Shirley Smith's work.